all right
[Music]
the question does egg feeding in other
words dietary cholesterol affect the
level of cholesterol in the blood was
answered 40 years ago give someone half
a cup of eggs a day and within two three
four weeks their cholesterol keeps going
up and then stop the eggs by switching
to an egg substitute and the cholesterol
comes down or start people on the egg
substitute and not much happens but then
start feeding eggs and their cholesterol
shoots right up
put people on a cholesterol-free diet
and their cholesterols drop but then add
some egg yolk cholesterol and their
cholesterol goes up take it away and
their cholesterol goes down you could do
this all year
and it's within days 10 days of eggs and
cholesterol shot up 50 points take the
eggs away and it comes back down you can
reproduce this effect over and over and
over and over
though evidently penguin omelets are
only about half as deadly
switch people from a high cholesterol
diet to a cholesterol free diet and you
can drop blood cholesterol levels as
much as a hundred points
okay but that was giving people more
than a half cup of egg yolks a day but
even just a single egg a day can
increase people's LDL cholesterol 12
percent
put all the studies together in this
2020 meta-analysis more than 50 or
randomized controlled trials feeding
people eggs and egg consumption
significantly increases LDL cholesterol
period
now studies funded by the egg board use
a variety of methods to try to minimize
the reported negative health effects of
eggs by for example claiming the dietary
cholesterol affects only certain people
that's actually been put to the test and
only three percent were even potentially
non-responders to dietary cholesterol
and even these probably evidence some
adverse response
wait then how was the egg board able to
design a study in which egg intake did
not change blood cholesterol
by feeding them sufficiently large
quantities of dairy and meat uh see
there's a plateau effect they're all
lines of evidence converged indicate
that dietary cholesterol is a major
factor in promoting hardening of the
arteries confusion about dietary
cholesterol has arisen because above a
certain ceiling you basically max out
cholesterol absorption check it out if
you're eating a strictly plant-based
diet with a baseline of zero cholesterol
intake and you start adding meat derrier
eggs to your diet you can get a dramatic
rise in blood cholesterol but as your
diet starts out more and more meaty you
can saturate your system it basically
max out on the additional effect so no
wonder the egg board packed in the extra
meat and dairy to mask the egg effect
a systematic review of egg industry
funding and cholesterol research sought
out to see if industry-funded studies
were more likely to report conclusions
that were not supported by their own
objective findings
of the non-industry-funded studies and
the effect of egg ingestion on
cholesterol cholesterol increases were
reported in about 90 percent among
industry-funded studies cholesterol
increases were reported in about 90
percent in other words even the egg
industry funded study showed eggs
increased blood cholesterol and not a
single study funded by anyone showed a
significant decrease okay but here's the
crazy part about half of the
industry-funded studies reported
conclusions that were discordant with
their own results in other words they
found that cholesterol went up but if
you read their conclusions they
exonerated eggs that's why you can't
just read the abstract you actually have
to see what they found readers editors
in the public should remain alert to
funding sources in interpreting study
findings and conclusions
foreign